Olubunmi Ruth Alao

♦ http://bumsyalao.me/ ■ bumsyalao@gmail.com ♦ /bumsyalao bumsyalao +971501507152

3+ years of experience in web application development, working mostly with JavaScript; React as frontend framework and NodeJS as backend solution. I understand business requirements, prioritise work based on highest business value and work with teams to solve problems.

Relevant Experience

Software Developer (contractor) at IBM

Dec 2018 - Present

Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

I worked on the TAMM Project here In Abu Dhabi. It is an impactful project aiming to revolutionise how citizens of Abu Dhabi interact with government services.

Built highly optimisied frontend visualisation of investement data using charts, graphs, highly interactive investment maps and business calculators for potential business investors.

Managed business processes with camunda business process modeler, while following agile software programming practices. Wrote Frontend and Backend tests.



Software Developer at Andela NG

Aug 2017 - Feb 2018 EFT Specialist at Interswitch NG

LoopBackJS

Remote & Freelancing

Production servers

Developer portal.

network traffic.

NodeJS

Jan 2016 - Aug 2017

2018

React

IBM API Connect

I built Full stack applications using Micro-service for frontend and backend architecture while following agile software programming practices.

Wrote Front-end, Back-end and E2E test.

Contributed to Reaction commerce open source.

Contributed to Cards For Humanity, a fast-paced online version of the popular card game, Cards Against Humanity.



Full FEP Deployment, Upgrades, Maintenance & Support of core banking systems (Postilion, Postcard, Postilion Office).

HSM (Hardware Security Module) Deployment.

Channel Enhancement & Certification (ATM, POS, WEB, and Mobile). Integration to external systems and networks. Examples: Integration to Processors/Switches (MasterCard, VISA, VERVE).

I Worked remotely with engineering teams to build web applications

I worked on Stanbic Bank IBM APIC; Deployment of UAT, Test and

Set up network servers for the API Gateway DB, API manager and

Set up load balancers, to connect with the API cloud and manage

IBM Cloud

Networking

Installing, managing, upgrading and administering Microsoft SQL databases



Education

Covenant University

2010 - 2014

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

CGPA: 4.43/5

Final year project: A Computing Platform for Metabolic Network Visualization and Topological Analysis.

Selected Personal Projects

The-Consent-Game 2019 Post-It 2017

The consent game is built for The Consent Workshop, to teach young adults about consent.

React Redux SCSS Javascript ES6 The-Consent-Game

Post-it is a simple application that allows users create groups and post messages to group.

NodeJS React Redux SCSS PostgresSQL Javascript ES6 opost-it

Ideabox

Ideabox is a simple application that allows users to create a pool of

A game of love and prediction.

Ideabox is a simple application that allows users to create a pool of ideas and promote collaboration.

NodeJS React Redux SCSS Mongoose Javascript ES6 Sideabox

HTML CSS Javascript SFlames

Selected Awards and Certifications

Front-End Web Developer 2018 Microsoft Certified Professional 2016

Udacity Microsoft License 13392204

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification

2017 Python- codecademy

See certificate

Codecademy

Postilion Basic Traning 2016

ACI worldwide